athlinks.com 2013-05-27

# Athlinks - Privacy Policy

## Athlinks Privacy Policy

##### This policy is effective as of November 1, 2006.

We built Athlinks to make it easy to share information with your friends and fellow athletes. We understand you may not want everyone in the world to have the information you share on Athlinks; that is why we give you control of your information. Our default privacy settings limit the information displayed in your profile to your networks and other reasonable community limitations that we tell you about. 

### Athlinks follows two core principles:

**1\. You should have control over your personal information.**   
Athlinks helps you share information with your friends and fellow endurance athletes. You choose what information you put in your profile, including contact and personal information, pictures, interests and groups you join. And you control with whom you share that information through the privacy settings on the each bit of content uploaded to the site. 

**2\. You should have access to the information others want to share.**   
There is an increasing amount of information available on the Internet, and you may want to know what relates to you, your friends, and people around you. We want to help you easily get that information. 

Sharing information should be easy. And we want to provide you with the privacy tools necessary to control how and with whom you share that information. If you have questions or ideas, please contact us. 

### Athlinks's Privacy Policy

Athlinks's Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you decide to share, and help you make informed decisions when using Athlinks located at www.athlinks.com ("Athlinks" or "Web Site"). 

By using or accessing Athlinks, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

### The Information We Collect

When you visit Athlinks you provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected by us and Web Site use information collected by us as you interact with our Web Site. 

When you register with Athlinks, you provide us with certain personal information, such as your name, your email address, your gender, date of birth, and city/state/province/country of residence. We use this information to gather your results data and automatically merge it with your member profile based these criteria. 

When you enter Athlinks, we collect your browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all Athlinks visitors. In addition, we store certain information from your browser using "cookies." A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in. These cookies terminate once the user closes the browser. By default, we use a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you come back to Athlinks. You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenience feature. 

When you use Athlinks, you may form relationships, send messages, perform searches and queries, form groups, set up events, and transmit information through various channels. We collect this information so that we can provide you the service and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent or easily see your friend list. 

You post User Content (as defined in the Athlinks [Terms of Use](http://www.athlinks.com/helpTermsOfUse.aspx)) on the Site at your own risk. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other Users with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that User Content you post on the Site will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Content. 

Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on Athlinks is a violation of the Athlinks Terms of Service and should be reported on our contact us page. 

If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Athlinks stores this information to send this one-time email, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us to request that we remove this information from our database. 

Athlinks also collects race results from outside sources in order to provide you with a complete user experience as an endurance athlete and a more personalized experience. 

By using Athlinks, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States. 

### Children Under Age 13

Athlinks does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on Athlinks. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us. 

### Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18

We recommend that minors over the age of 13 ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet. 

### Use of Information Obtained by Athlinks

When you register with Athlinks, you create your own profile and privacy settings. Your profile information, as well as your name, age, gender, and photo, are displayed to people in the networks specified in your privacy settings to enable you to connect with people on Athlinks. We may occasionally use your name and email address to send you notifications regarding new services offered by Athlinks that we think you may find valuable. We do not ever give out this contact information either on the site or in private or public communications. All messages sent through the site use Athlinks’ proprietary messaging system in order to hide at all times your email address. 

Profile information is used by Athlinks primarily to be presented back to and edited by you when you access the service and to be presented to others permitted to view that information by your privacy settings. In some cases where your privacy settings permit it (e.g., posting to your wall), other Athlinks users may be able to supplement your profile. 

Profile information you submit to Athlinks will be available to users of Athlinks who belong to at least one of the networks you allow to access the information through your privacy settings (e.g., school, geography, friends of friends). Your name, alias, and profile picture thumbnail will be available in search results across the Athlinks network and those limited pieces of information may be made available to third party search engines. This is primarily so your friends can find you and send a friend request. People who see your name in searches, however, will not be able to access your profile information you choose to make that information public which allows such access based on your privacy settings. 

Athlinks will send you only service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service. For instance, if a friend sends you a new message, requests you as a confirmed friend, or someone posts on your wall, you will receive an email alerting you to that fact. 

Athlinks may use information in your profile without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as aggregating how many people in a race event or group use particular gear or for personalizing advertisements and promotions so that we can provide them to you on Athlinks where appropriate. We do this to cut down on the amount of unrelated advertisements and increase the relevancy of advertisements that are shown to you. 

### Sharing Your Information with Third Parties

Athlinks is about sharing information with others — friends and people in your networks — while providing you with controls that restrict other third parties from accessing your information. We allow you to choose the information you provide to friends and networks through Athlinks. Our network architecture and your privacy settings allow you to make informed choices about who has access to your information. We do not provide contact information to third party marketers. We share your information with third parties only in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is 1) reasonably necessary to offer the service, 2) legally required or, 3) permitted by you. 

Unlike most sites on the Web, Athlinks limits access to site information by third party search engine "crawlers" (e.g. Google, Yahoo, MSN, Ask). Athlinks blocks access by these engines to personal information beyond your name, profile picture, and limited aggregated data about your profile (e.g. number of wall postings). 

We may provide information to service providers to help us bring you the services we offer. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business, such as to host the service at a co-location facility for servers, to send out email updates about Athlinks, to remove repetitive information from our user lists, to process payments for products or services, or to provide search results or links (including sponsored links). In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time in connection with these business activities. Where we utilize third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the Athlinks-specified purposes. 

We may be required to disclose user information pursuant to lawful requests, such as subpoenas or court orders, or in compliance with applicable laws. We do not reveal information until we have a good faith belief that an information request by law enforcement or private litigants meets applicable legal standards. Additionally, we may share account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with law, to protect our interests or property, to prevent fraud or other illegal activity perpetrated through the Athlinks service or using the Athlinks name, or to prevent imminent bodily harm. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, agents or government agencies. 

We let you choose to share information with marketers or electronic commerce providers through sponsored groups or other on-site offers. 

We may offer stores or provide services jointly with other companies on Athlinks. You can tell when another company is involved in any store or service provided on Athlinks, and we may share customer information with that company in connection with your use of that store or service. 

If the ownership of all or substantially all of the Athlinks business, or individual business units owned by Athlinks, Inc., were to change, your user information may be transferred to the new owner so the service can continue operations. In any such transfer of information, your user information would remain subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy. 

### Links

Athlinks may contain links to other websites. We are of course not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Athlinks. 

### Third Party Advertising

Advertisements that appear on Athlinks are sometimes delivered (or "served") directly to users by third party advertisers. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third party advertisers may also download cookies to your computer, or use other technologies such as JavaScript and "web beacons" (also known as "1x1 gifs") to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows the advertising network to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. Athlinks does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third party advertisers. Third party advertisers have no access to your contact information stored on Athlinks unless you choose to share it with them. 

This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by Athlinks and does not cover the use of cookies or other tracking technologies by any of its advertisers. 

For help on cookies, [click here](http://www.athlinks.com/helpCookies.aspx). 

### Changing or Removing Information

Access and control over most personal information on Athlinks is readily available through the profile editing tools. Athlinks users may modify or remove any of their profile information at any time by logging into their account. Information will be updated immediately. Individuals who wish to deactivate their Athlinks account may do so on the [Settings](http://www.athlinks.com/settings.aspx) page. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to members of Athlinks. 

Where you make use of the communication features of the service to share information with other individuals on Athlinks, however, (e.g., posting on someone else's Wall) you generally cannot remove such communications. 

### Security

Athlinks takes appropriate precautions to protect our users' information. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. Because email and instant messaging are not recognized as secure communications, we request that you not send private information to us by email or instant messaging services. If you have any questions about the security of Athlinks Web Site, please contact us. 

### Terms of Use, Notices and Revisions

If you choose to visit Athlinks, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of, and application of law of the state of Arizona. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use at any time. Non-material changes and clarifications will take effect immediately, and material changes will take effect within 30 days of their posting on this site. If we make changes, we will post them and will indicate at the top of this page the policy's effective date. We therefore encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. 

### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us. You may also contact us by mail at  2040 S. Alma School Rd. Ste 1 #148 Chandler, AZ 85248 .
